Guide to the Benjamin Newton Duke Papers, 1834-1984, bulk 1884-1929.
The Benjamin Newton Duke papers 1834-1984 bulk 1884-1929.
- Financial Papers, 1884-1924, undated, (46 containers)
  - Insurance policies, 1913-1914
    Additional oversize materials in Box 149.
  - Rents: Marc Anthony Apartments, 1913, July-Dec.
  - Stock certificates, 1887-1917
  - Stock transactions:
    Oversize materials in Box 149.
    - 1913,1914, undated (by broker)
    - 1909-1919, undated (by stock), (2 folders)
  - Tax Statements, 1914-1926
  - Trial balances:
    - Angier B. Duke, 1915
    - Benjamin Newton Duke, 1912-1914 (see also Box 113, W. Duke, Sons & Co. Cashbook)
  - James B. Duke, 1912-1914, (3 folders)
  - Miscellaneous, 1914
  - Alaska Dredging and Power Co.: (Box 113)
    - Minute book, 1907-1908
    - Stock certificates book, 1907
  - Duke Farm, Orange Co., N.C., Expenditures, 1897-1909
  - Solomon River Hydraulic Mining Co.:
    - Minutes, by-laws, incorporation, 1905
    - Common stock, 1905, Preferred stock, 1905-1906
  - W. Duke, Sons & Co. Cashbook, 1891
  - Check Stubs: (Box 114)
    - A.J.D. Biddle, Jr., 1919 (1 vol.)
    - Mary Duke Biddle, 1915-1918 (1 vol.)
    - Angier B. Duke, 1914-1917 (4 vols.)
  - Check Stubs: Angier B. Duke, 1917-1918 (4 vols.) (Box 115)
  - Check Stubs: Benjamin N. Duke, 1901-1918 (4 vols.) (Box 116)
  - Deposit slips, 1915-1918 (Box 117)
  - Invoice book (disbound), 1892-1893 (Box 118)
  - Invoice book (disbound), 1893-1898 (Box 119)
  - Invoice book (disbound), 1893-1898 (Box 120)
  - Stock journal, 1899-1901 (Box 121)
  - Stock ledger, 1899-1901 (Box 122)
- Legal Papers Series, 1834-1928, undated, (2 containers)
  Majority pertain to property transactions of various people, including Benjamin Newton Duke, in Orange County and Durham, N.C. Other papers include charters for businesses, insurance policies, a legal brief, and a copy of Washington Duke's will. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Agreements: Southern Railway Co.--water pipeline, electric lights for B.N. Duke, 1900, 1902 (Box 123)
  - Asheville Ice and Coal Co., Act to Incorporate, 1891, May 2
  - Complaint: Richard H. Wright against J.B. Duke,; B.N. Duke,; B.L. Duke,; G.W. Hill, 1891 (summons)
  - Contract:
    - H.J. Blauvent, Architect, and B.N. Duke, 1901
    - Conservatory of Music: specifications for heating, 1899 (see also OC:II:4)
    - Methodist Church, Durham, N.C., undated
  - Deeds, 1834-1918, undated, (16 folders)
  - Land plats, 1884-1912, undated (see also OC:II:4)
  - Doris Duke Trust: Indenture and deed of trust, 1924;additions, 1925 (Box 124)
  - Estate: Angier B. Duke, 1926 (distribution)
  - Fidelity and Deposit Co. of Maryland: bond, 1894-1905
  - Stock transactions, 1896-1900
  - Trust funds: Washington Duke, for:
    - Annie and Robert Duke, 1904, Oct. 10
    - Family servants, 1904, Oct. 10
  - Trust Indenture: Benjamin N. Duke to Allen,; Flowers,; Sands, 1926
  - Will: Washington Duke, 1905 (transcript copy)
  - Will/Estate: Benjamin N. Duke, 1926-1930
- Pictures Series, 1870s-1927, 1960s, undated, 6 containers
  Photographs and blueprints. Photographs include family albums, a series of views of the Duke Farm in Orange County and Four Acres in Durham, and individuals. Blueprints include the Pigeon River Power Plant Project, Duke Farm stables, and an addition to the Southern Conservatory of Music. Arranged by category: albums, people, and buildings.
  - Albums
    - Albums, ca. 1870s-1900s (1 vol.) (Box 125)
    - Albums, ca. 1870s-1900s (1 vol.) (Box 126)
    - Duke farm, Orange County, N.C., 1910-1919, 1985, undated (Box 127)
  - People
    - Biddle, Mary Duke, ca. 1897-1910 (Box 128)
    - Duke, Angier Buchanan, ca. 1890s-1915
    - Duke, Benjamin Newton:
      - ca. 1880s-1920s
      - With wife, Sarah, St. Petersburg, Fla., 1914
      - Birthday party, ca. 1916
      - Funeral, 1929
      - With others, Lookout Mountain, Tenn., 1892
    - Duke, Cordelia Biddle with children: Angier Biddle and Anthony Drexel Duke and Mary Duke Biddle, ca. 1920
    - Duke, Sarah Pearson Angier, ca. 1870s-1920s (see also OC:II:4)
    - Duke, Washington with great-grandchildren, ca. 1900
    - People:
      - Atlantic City--Boardwalk, 1924 (includes B.N. Duke,; J.B. Duke,; M.D. Biddle,; Lily Parrish Flowers,; Robert Lee Flowers)
      - Miscellaneous, ca. 1890s-1896 (includes Prof. Doud,; J.B. Duke,; John Acero Angier,; James Haywood Southgate,; Reuben Oscar Everett)
      - Unidentified, undated
    - Portraits (photographs of) Lady Georgiana North,; Lady Mary Reynolds, undated
  - Buildings
    - Buildings (including houses), ca. 1896, ca. 1912, undated
    - Carriage House/Stable: H.J. Blauvelt, architect for B.N. Duke, ca. 1910-1920s
    - Church(es) and cemetery, 1986, undated (includes Moses Hester's Church)
    - Duke University, East Campus, construction, ca. 1925
    - Duke's Chapel, construction, 1926
    - Fairview, Durham, N.C., ca. 1890s
    - Four Acres ( exteriors), ca. 1910, (4 folders)
    - Four Acres: (Box 129)
      - Prior to demolition, 1961
      - Exteriors, including gardens, undated
    - Irvington-on-the-Hudson, Tarrytown, N.Y., undated
    - Kittrell College: B.N. Duke Library, 1969 (color slides)
    - Limestone College, Gaffney, S.C., 1926
    - New Hope Creek: Duke Quarry ( near Hillsborough), ca. 1926
    - Roney family: Birthplace of Artelia (Roney) Duke, including Boyd's Creek and Stonewall Spring, ca. 1920s
    - Underpass, Chapel Hill St., Durham, N.C., construction, 1926, June
    - Y.W.C.A., Durham, N.C., 1927
    - Fragile: (Box 130)
      - Mirror with photographs attached ( Washington Duke and his children, Mary
      - Duke Lyon,; Brodie L. Duke,; James B. Duke,; Benjamin Newton Duke), undated
      - Photograph: B.N. Duke,; Sarah Duke, undated
- Richard B. Arrington Papers Series, 1905-1914, (2 containers)
  Relates to personal and financial interests of Arrington, secretary and business agent for Benjamin Newton Duke. Much of the correspondence, including enclosed bills and receipts, relates to the construction of his home in White Plains, N.Y. Business papers concern his stock dealings and after his death, his estate. The correspondence is arranged chronologically, followed by the letterbook. Papers related to financial interests are arranged alphabetically.
  - Correspondence, 1905, Nov. 9-1914, Apr., (11 folders) (Box 131)
  - Letterbook, 1903, Dec. 16-1906, Aug. 3 (Box 132)
  - Financial papers:
    - Accounts, 1907-1913
    - Check stubs, 1913, Mar.-Apr.
    - Receipts, 1905-1913, (2 folders)
- Alexander H. Sands, Jr., Papers Series, 1910-1918, (6 containers)
  A secretary/business agent for Benjamin Newton Duke, these papers relate to Mr. Sands's personal and financial interests. Much of the correspondence is concerned with his business interests and the support of his wife and his parents. Business papers include check registers, check stubs, and receipts. Correspondence is arranged chronologically, followed by the letterbook. Business records are arranged alphabetically.
  - Correspondence, 1910, Apr.-1915 (Box 133)
  - Letterbooks, 1910-1918 (2 vols.) (Box 134)
  - Financial Papers: (Box 135)
    - Accounts: Southern Audit Co. of New York, Inc., 1914-1915
    - Check registers: 1912-1918
  - Financial Papers: Check stubs, 1910, Apr.-1915 (Box 136)
  - Financial Papers: (Box 137)
    - Check stubs, 1915-1917 (5 vols.)
    - Reyhing & Co., 1914
  - Financial Papers: (Box 138)
    - Daybook, 1914-1915
    - Ledger, 1914-1915
    - Receipts, 1913-1915, (4 folders)
- Miscellaneous Papers Series, 1880-1984, undated, (7 containers)
  Includes Sarah Pearson Angier Duke's diary (1927-1929); clippings; genealogical material; material pertaining to funerals, memorials, and tributes; printed material; scrapbook; recipes; and tobacco/cigarette flavorings. Arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material. Printed material is arranged alphabetically by company name and relates to business and philanthropic interests throughout the United States.
  - Alpha Tau Omega Fraternity, 1904 (Pledge class?) (Box 139)
  - Bible: New Testament, undated: C.L. Mitchell to R.L. Flowers, 1925
  - Clippings, 1890-1984, undated, (4 folders)
  - Clothing pattern: See OC:II:4 Miscellaneous
  - Diary, 1927-1929 (Sarah Pearson Angier Duke)
  - Diploma: Trinity Park High School, 1903, June (Mary Lillian Duke)
    - See: OC:II:4 Miscellaneous
  - Funeral:
    - Benjamin N. Duke, 1929, (3 folders)
    - Sarah Pearson Angier Duke, 1936
  - Genealogical information: Duke family, 1916-1937,undated
  - Memorials: (Box 140)
    - Angier B. Duke, 1923-1924 (includes Plato Tracy Durham Poem)
    - James Buchanan Duke, 1926, (2 folders)
  - Poetry (Misc.), undated includes prayer, 1907 ( John C. Kilgo to B.N. Duke)
  - Printed Material:
    - American Cigar Co., 1913-1914
    - American Machine and Foundry Co., 1912-1913
    - American Snuff Co., 1905-1915
    - The American Tobacco Co.:
      - 1890-1915
      - Code book, #6 ( 1902)
    - American Trust Co., 1907-1914
    - American Type Founders Co, 1898-1914
  - Printed Material: (Box 141)
    - Bank of Harnett, Duke, N.C., 1906-1915
    - Banking, 1906-1915, undated
    - British-American Tobacco Co., Ltd., 1912-1915
    - Canal Bank & Trust Co., New Orleans, 1914-1916
    - The Chatham and Phenix National Bank of N.Y., 1911-1914
    - Churches, 1887-1977
    - The Citizens National Bank of Durham, N.C., 1905-1911
    - Colleges, Schools, Universities, 1901-1940, (2 folders)
    - Consolidated Tobacco Co., 1903
    - Cotton Mills, 1894-1914
    - Dixie Fire Insurance Co., 1907-1916
    - The Fidelity Bank of Durham, N.C.:
      - 1905-1919
      - Plaque, 1922
    - George W. Helme Co., 1911-1915
    - Georgia Railway and Power Co., 1914-1915
    - German-American National Bank of New Orleans, 1911-1913
    - Great Falls Power Co., 1911-1913
    - Guaranty Trust Co. of N.Y., 1910-1915
    - The Hanover National Bank of N.Y.C., 1912-1914
    - Hudson and Manhattan Railroad Co., 1911-1916
  - Printed Material: (Box 142)
    - Imperial Tobacco Co.:
      - Canada, Ltd., 1914-1915
      - Great Britain and Ireland, 1914
    - Insurance, 1906-1915, undated
    - Jim Butler Tonopah Mining Co., 1904-1915
    - Kansas City, Mexico and Orient Railway Co., 1905-1914,undated
    - Liggett and Meyers Tobacco Co., 1911-1918
    - Lincoln Memorial University, 1927-1939 (see also oversize material)
    - MacAndrews and Forbes Co., 1912-1914
    - Masonic journal, 1902, 1936-1939
    - Mellon National Bank, 1913-1914
    - Mining, 1902-1915
    - Miscellaneous businesses, 1901-1915, undated
    - Moore & Schley: Code Books #2, #3, 1906
    - Morton Trust Co., 1900-1910
    - National Bank of Commerce in New York, 1912-1916
    - North Carolina Society of New York, 1913-1915
    - Odell Manufacturing Co., Concord, N.C., 1908, undated
  - Printed Material: (Box 143)
    - P. Lorillard Co., 1911-1914
    - Peace Congress, 1908, undated
    - Porto Rican American Tobacco Co., 1912-1915
    - Public Utilities, 1911-1916
    - R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co., 1912-1915
    - Railroads, 1904-1915, (2 folders)
    - Real Estate, 1901-1915
    - Republic Iron and Steel Co., 1899-1913
    - Seaboard Air Line Railway, 1900-1915
    - The Second National Bank:
      - City of N.Y., 1908-1915
      - Somerville, N.J., 1912-1915
    - Social Welfare agencies, 1904-1923, undated
    - The Southern Cotton Oil Co., 1907-1908
    - Southern Pacific Co., 1909-1914
    - Southern Power Co., 1909-1914
    - Southern Railway Co., 1906-1915
    - Tobacco, 1880-1912, undated
    - Union Exchange Bank, 1903-1914
    - Virginia-Carolina Chemical Co., 1900-1915
    - Weyman-Bruton Co., 1912-1918
    - Chronological file, 1880-1964, undated
  - Recipes: Sarah Pearson Angier Duke, ca. 1880s-1930s (Box 144)
  - Scrapbook: Theater record, 1898-1899 ( Mary Lillian Duke)
  - Tobacco/Cigarette flavorings, 1896
  - Tributes: Benjamin Newton Duke ( see also oversize material)
    - Chanticleer, 1913 (vol. 2)
    - A Celebration of the Life of B.N. Duke, 1979:
      - Audiotape (reel-to-reel master)
      - Photographs
      - Printed material
  - Tributes: A Celebration of the Life of B.N. Duke, 1979 (2 presentation sets) (Box 145)
- Oversize Material Series
  Oversize materials in Box 149 and in OC:II:4.
  - Financial Papers Series
    - Stocks, Bonds and Dividends Record, 1912-1918:
      - Angier B. Duke,; Mary Duke Biddle,; Sarah Pearson Duke,; Anthony J.D. Biddle, Jr. (Box 149)
    - Stocks, Bonds and Dividends Record, 1892-1918:
      - Benjamin N. Duke (Box 149)
    - Stocks, Bonds and Dividends Record, 1913-1915:
      - Southern Investment Co. of Canada, Ltd. (Box 149)
  - Miscellaneous Series
    - Clippings, 1902, undated (scrapbook) (Box 149)
    - Funeral: In Memoriam, 1929 (condolences, clippings, telegrams, etc. on the death of Benjamin Newton Duke) (Box 149)
    - Tribute: Benjamin Newton Duke on his birthday April 27, 1923,by Trinity College:
      - Vol. 1: Correspondence (Box 149)
      - Vol. 2: Trinity College photographs. (Box 149)
  - Correspondence Series (Box 149)
    - Plats (removed from correspondence), 1902-1905, 1907, 1909, 1912-1913 (Box 149)
  - Financial Papers Series: Miscellaneous
    - Account [unidentified rental property], 1914-1915 (Box 149)
    - Blueprint map of North Carolina/South Carolina, undated (unidentified, may be of power plant sites) (Box 149)
    - First National Bank of Winston, N.C. (Box 149)
      - Balance at close of business July 5, 1893 (Box 149)
    - The Pullman Co.: Commissary supplies for private coach:
      - Grassmere, March-April 1906 (Box 149)
  - Pictures Series
    - Duke, Sarah Pearson Angier, ca. 1890s, 1906 (oval portraits) (Box 149)
    - Duke Farms, Orange Co., N.C., ( Plat), undated. Hand-drawn. (Opaperfolder 1)
    - Duke Farms, Stables, Orange Co., N.C., and New York, N.Y. (2 folders) 1901 (Box 149)
    - Pigeon River Power Plant: Project Plans, 1923 (Box 149)
    - Southern Conservatory of Music ( addition), undated (Opaperfolder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Series (Box 149)
    - Clothing pattern, Benjamin Newton Duke, undated (Box 149)
    - Diploma: Trinity Park High School, June 6, 1903 (Mary Duke Biddle) (Box 149)
    - Lincoln Memorial University: Honorary degree to Benjamin Newton Duke, undated (Box 149)
    - Oglethorpe University: Honorary degree to Benjamin Newton Duke, May 30, 1926 (Box 149)
    - Resolution of Thanks: Oxford Orphan Asylum to Benjamin Newton Duke, undated (Box 149)
    - Resolution of Appreciation to Mr. and Mrs. B.N. Duke from guests at Cateret Lodge, Jan. 1, 1903 (Opaperfolder 2)